

7521 Woodthrush Dr., Dallas, TX 214-399-0458 sanwill.sw@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Exhibits exemplary work ethic, dependability, and willingness to learn new processes, skills, and techniques that enhance business and team efforts. Hardworking healthcare professional offering 11+ years of organizational experience in clinical, supervisory, and administrative/leadership roles. Highly efficient, productive and reliable. Seeking to help companies meet their goals.

SKILLS

• Payroll

· Chart auditing

· Microsoft Office Suite

· Problem Solving

Teamwork

· Building effective relationships

EXPERIENCE

Staff RN IV Therapy

February 2019 - Current

ST. DOMINICS HOSPITAL | Jackson, MS

- Use advanced ultrasound to ensure the most appropriate device selection and increased accuracy of peripheral vascular access device placement in adults.
- Ensure proper placement of PICC line for use.
- Provide education and instruction to nursing staff on care and maintenance of PICC lines.
- Monitor patients and identify and solve problems related to the line.
- BARD Sherlock PICC tip confirmation technology used.
- 98% success rate using a combination of over 100 BARD PICC and Powerglide Midline products.

RN Category Manager, Supply Chain Management
UNIVERSITY OF MISSISSIPPI MEDICAL CENTER | Jackson, MS

November 2018 - Current

- Responsible for providing Supply Chain leadership and support and serve as a supply chain liaison between clinicians and the Supply Chain Department.
- Provide active leadership and support Value Analysis Teams (VAT). Serve as co-chair for Procedural and Lab VAT
 Committees in efforts to achieve target annual savings goals.
- Guide and maintain the integrity of the public procurement processes to ensure compliance with legislative mandates and procurement policies and procedures by reviewing and monitoring procurements conducted by any designee, department, agency, or official.
- Develop and conduct internal procurement training.

- Actively assist departments in the management of commodity and contract service expenses. Identifies and
 communicated spend variances and assists in the development of strategic sourcing initiatives to reduce costs,
 increase revenue, and improve patient outcomes.
- Assist UMMC departments in the development, financial analysis, and processing of department contracts for clinical commodities and contract services. Responsible for assisting with over 65 multi-term contracts totaling at \$1M plus.
- Work with the VAT committees and Contracts Administration department in the negotiation of contracts, development of RFPs, and support of competitive Bids.
- Prepare and issue solicitation documents to include request for proposals (RFPs), and invitation for bids (IFBs), and Sole Source documents. Receive and evaluate RFPs and IFBs as well as award or recommend the award of contracts. Currently in the preliminary preparation and solicitation of an RFP for pharmacy distribution services with a projected 5-year spend of \$600M.
- Facilitate utilization of data collection, market research, and spend analytics as best practice for UMMC strategic sourcing process. Utilize Emergency Care Research Institute (ECRI) research and market intelligence sources and to identify and ensure most cost effective and competitive pricing for the purchase of supplies and services.
- Review and prepare financial analyses to determine DFA/ Institutional of Higher Learning (IHL) thresholds, spend compliance, and financial impact of product conversions, new product requests, and new contracts/contract renewals.
- Use Excel and Access to determine spend analytics, analyze commodity utilization, and track contract/market share compliance.
- Collaborate with GPOs and suppliers to develop strategic opportunities and partnerships to support established financial targets.
- Work with the Purchasing Department to assure that all strategic initiatives are implemented and monitored to assure the expected value is realized.
- Serve on 340B Pharmacy Program and Pharmacy and Therapeutic Committees.
- Perform other related duties to ensure the accomplishment of the goals and objectives of the Purchasing Department.

RN II - PICC/ Adult Vascular Access

November 2017 - February 2019

UNIVERSITY OF MISSISSIPPI MEDICAL CENTER | Jackson, MS

- Used advanced ultrasound to ensure the most appropriate device selection and increased accuracy of peripheral vascular access device placement in adults.
- Ensured proper placement of PICC line for use.
- · Provided education and instruction to nursing staff on care and maintenance of PICC lines.
- Monitored patients and identified and solved problems related to the line.
- Vasanova (VPS) PICC tip confirmation technology used.
- 95% success rate using over 400 Arrow PICC and Powerglide Midline products.
- One's introduction of Vascular Access Board Certification (VA-BC) to University of Mississippi Medical Center played
 a significant role in its approval as the accepted certification and professional standard for current and new
 vascular access professionals employed in the Adult Vascular Access Department.

RN House Supervisor May 2015 - March 2018

MISSISSIPPI BAPTIST MEDICAL CENTER | Jackson, MS

Provided administrative leadership level nursing in a 650-bed hospital during off-shifts, weekends, and holidays.

Performed administrative oversight to over 150 nursing/ancillary staff to include:

- Coordination and facilitation of patient flow on multiple units to include appropriate bed assignments based on workload and patient acuity.
- · Coordination and reallocation of staffing and nursing resources according patient needs.
- Identification and resolution of daily operational and clinical issues that impacted the quality of patient care and overall hospital performance.
- Direction and oversight to all emergency codes and drills and escalated issues per chain of command when indicated.
- Off-tour patient service recovery.
- Compliance monitoring with unit-based performance improvement efforts.

Health Science Core I Instructor

January 2017 - July 2017

HINDS COUNTY CAREER AND TECHNICAL CENTER | Raymond, MS

· As a contract employee, taught health science introductory curriculum to high school students.

Medical Surgical /Telemetry Nurse Manager

September 2016 - January 2017

MERIT HEALTH CENTRAL | Jackson, MS

- Provided nursing leadership over a 32-bed medical-surgical unit.
- Upon unit closure, transferred to Burn ICU to provide direct nursing care within a critical care setting for individuals with various burn injuries and limb injuries requiring revascularization procedures.

Assistant Director/Director of Nursing

July 2015- August 2016

MILLCREEK REHABILITATION CENTER | Magee, MS

Under the supervision of the facility CEO/Administrator, served as Nursing Director of a 57-bed psychiatric residential treatment facility to ensure the provision of 24/7 nursing care according Federal and State standards and regulations.

- Performed administrative oversight to 20 employees.
- · Facilitated policy design, development, and implementation to improve care delivery processes.
- Responsible for the hiring, education, and discipline of nursing/ancillary staff.
- Performed periodic and annual performance appraisals.
- Performed monthly chart audits to produce corporate compliance reports (93% compliance above 90% threshold-for seven consecutive months).
- Completed initial and annual Medicaid assessment reports for Individuals with Intellectual Disabilities.
- Produced safety event and investigative reports to Centers for Medicaid Services.

As Assistant Director of Nursing:

- Aided in the design, implementation, and evaluation of nursing and policies to ensure consistent delivery of care.
- Served as treatment team nurse and collaborated with other disciplines to ensure medical and psychiatric treatments were implemented according to Medicaid regulations.
- Performed monthly chart audits to produce corporate compliance reports.
- · Coordinated weekly educational in-services to ensure compliance with Medicaid regulations.
- Completed initial/annual Medicaid assessment reports for Individuals with Intellectual Disabilities.

Staff RN- OR Circulator August 2013 - May 2015

MISSISSIPPI BAPTIST MEDICAL CENTER | Jackson, MS

Under the guidance of the Mississippi State Board of Nursing and utilization of the nursing process:

- Provided direct patient care within the operating room patient based on procedure or surgery type according hospital policy and guidelines.
- Worked collaboratively with surgeons, anesthesiologists, CRNAs, and surgical techs during various surgical procedures.
- Functioned as evening RN supervisor to manage and coordinate surgery schedules activities utilizing over 25 surgical staff to provide health services effectively and productively for elective and emergent surgical procedures.
- Floated to endoscopy lab as needed to provide pediatric and adult patient admission and recovery for endoscopy and bronchoscopy procedures.

PICC Nurse April 2011 - August 2013

MISSISSIPPI BAPTIST MEDICAL CENTER | Jackson, MS

- Used advanced ultrasound to ensure the most appropriate device selection and increased accuracy of peripheral vascular access device placement in adults.
- Ensured proper placement of PICC line for use.
- Provided education and instruction to nursing staff on care and maintenance of PICC lines.
- Monitored patients and identified and solved problems related to the line.
- · Provided in-service and performed check-offs to nursing staff on the administration of Cathflo.
- Demonstrated a 96% successful placement rate of over 900 BARD and Navilyst PICCs using ultrasound guidance in the inpatient and outpatient settings.
- In 2013, fourth Registered Nurse in the state of Mississippi to achieve nationally-recognized Vascular Access Board Certification (VA-BC); first Mississippi Baptist Medical Center employee to achieve this certification.

MISSISSIPPI BAPTIST MEDICAL CENTER | Jackson, MS

Under the guidance of the Mississippi State Board of Nursing, adopted the nursing process to staff various units within the facility including: clinical specialty (IV/PICC, wound care), general medical-surgical, geri-psych, cardiac surgical, cardiac medical, neurology/ stroke, orthopedic surgery, ER observation, oncology units.

- · Analyzed records data and reports in order to identify health care needs and deliver optimum patient care.
- Prioritized patient care based on resource availability and need level.
- · Performed ordered nursing interventions for optimal patient outcomes and experience.
- Evaluated emergency situations and started appropriate nursing interventions.
- Demonstrated safe and responsible use of equipment; maintained infection control and safety measures with every single patient contact.
- Coordinated patient discharge with post-care instructions.

Staff RN - General Surgery

May 2008 - July 2009

MISSISSIPPI BAPTIST MEDICAL CENTER | Jackson, MS

Under the guidance of the Mississippi State Board of Nursing, adopted the nursing process to provide pre- and postsurgical nursing care to a variety of patients undergoing thoracotomy, gastrointestinal, genitourinary, thyroidectomy, mastectomy, amputation, and cosmetic surgical procedures.

- · Analyzed records data and reports in order to identify health care needs and deliver optimum patient care.
- Performed pre- and post-procedure nursing interventions for optimal patient outcomes and experience.
- Evaluated emergency situations and started appropriate nursing interventions.
- Assisted the physician with procedures, when needed.
- · Applied clinical expertise in wound care, intravenous therapy, catheterization, and pain management techniques.
- Demonstrated safe and responsible use of equipment; maintained infection control and safety measures with every single patient contact.
- · Coordinated patient discharge with post-care instructions.
- · Rotated night-shift Charge Nurse duties.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Nursing, Nurse Administrator Track

Anticipated Completion December 2019

South University, Savannah GA

MBA | Master of Business Administration

May 2018

Belhaven University, Jackson, MS

Bachelor of Science in Nursing

September 2014

Thomas Edison State University, Trenton, NJ

Associate of Applied Science in Nursing

May 2008

Hinds Community College, Raymond, MS

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Mississippi Purchasing Agents (CMPA)

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Certified, Basic Life Support (BLS)

Tuberculosis Surveillance and Testing Certification

AFFILIATIONS

Mississippi Association of Governmental Purchasing and Property Agents (MAGPPA)

MS Society of Certified Public Accountants (MSCPA)

American Institute of Certified Public Accountants (AICPA)

Mississippi Nurse's Association (MNA)

Association for Vascular Access (AVA)